# **Bradley Helphenstine, Senior Front-End Engineer**

Indiana, United States | +1 760 983 3605 | bradleyhelphenstine9608@gmail.com

## Summary

Proficient Senior Front-End Engineer offering 7 years of experience providing high-impact web solutions for diverse industry organizations. Skilled in designing, developing and testing multiple web-based applications incorporating a range of technologies. Proficient with CSS and JS Frameworks, with extensive knowledge of UX and User psychology. Aspiring to combine broad background with strong analytical and technical skills to excel as a Front-End Developer.

## **Work Experience**

## **Senior Front-End Engineer**

Aug 2022 – Current

Unitech Digital Studio (Remote) - London, UK

- Crafted **8+** custom websites using **React**, closely following client requirements and design documents, ensuring seamless functionality and user experience.
- Engineered front-end for 30+ user-friendly webpages using jQuery, JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS/Bootstrap, resulting in a 20% increase in user engagement.
- Enhanced user experience by creating interactive graphics with **Three.js**, leading to a **15%** increase in user interaction time.
- Collaborated with team members to manage the codebase, track changes, and ensure project integrity using **Git**, reducing code conflicts by **30%**.
- Mentored **2** junior developers on implementing cross-browser compatibility, conducting code reviews, and facilitating best practices, improving code quality by **25%**.

Front-End Developer Apr 2020 – July 2022

Alleo, IN, US

- Developed a company management admin panel using **Angular** and other modern technologies, streamlining internal operations for **50+** employees.
- Delivered responsive, cross-browser compatible and accessibility compliant websites, achieving **15%** faster load time than industry average.
- · Coordinated with designers to resolve **UX problems**, improve operations, and provide exceptional customer service.
- Used **JIRA** to track and resolve over **200+** user story and defects.

### **Junior Frontend Developer**

Oct 2017 - Mar 2020

ProLegion, IN, US

- · Created **10+** user-interactive web pages using **JavaScript**, **AngularJS**, and **Bootstrap**.
- Used advanced **JavaScript** to create a cross-browser compatible user interface.
- Built an automated testing infrastructure using **Selenium**, which reduced reports of bugs by **10%**.
- Communicated with back-end developers to resolve front-end issues, improving project delivery time by 10% through effective troubleshooting.
- Developed interactive UIs that surpassed client objectives, enhancing user experience and increasing user retention.

#### Education

## **Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science**

May 2013 - May 2017

Indiana University -- Bloomington, IN, USA

#### **Skills**

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Tailwind CSS

Frameworks/Libraries: React.js, Redux, Vue.js, Angular.js, Three.js, WebGL, Bootstrap

**Tools & Technologies**: Figma, Git, Webpack, JIRA, Selenium, Agile, Docker, Jenkins, Firebase, Vercel, Netlify **Design & Dev**: Responsive Web Design, UI/UX Best Practices, Component-Based Architecture, API Integration